<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on Richard A. Lent, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>/topics/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on Richard A. Lent, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 and beyond by Richard A. Lent. All rights reserved.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;me&#39; href=&#39;https://mastodon.social/@lentrichard&#39; style=&#39;text-decoration: none; font-size: 12px;&#39;&gt;Switch to Mastodon!&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 09:21:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/topics/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Multivariate Analysis with R</title>
      <link>/post/multivariate-analysis-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 09:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/multivariate-analysis-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Preliminaries Multivariate data A map Distance matrices Cluster analysis Mantel test Multidimensional scaling Principal components analysis Discriminant function analysis Epilogue      Reading time: 32 minute(s) @ 200 WPM.
Preliminaries  At some time or another, most users of statistics find themselves sitting in front of a large pile of computer output with the realization that it tells them nothing that they really want to know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to R</title>
      <link>/post/introduction-to-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 16:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/introduction-to-r/</guid>
      <description>Prologue Getting a feel for R The console Function calls and arguments HINT: Getting help  Some graphics HINT: Command history and workspace   Getting data into R Data frames Creating data frames HINT: Data management in R and RStudio.   Exploratory data analysis Scatterplot matrix HINT: R packages  Summary statistics and data screening Box plots Stem-and-leaf display Categorical variables: factors Some confirmatory analysis  More graphics R scripts (command files) An R menu system: R-commander Epilogue      Reading time: 23 minute(s) @ 200 WPM.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
