<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GIS on Richard A. Lent, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>/topics/gis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GIS on Richard A. Lent, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 and beyond by Richard A. Lent. All rights reserved.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;me&#39; href=&#39;https://ecoevo.social/@lentrichard&#39; style=&#39;text-decoration: none; font-size: 12px;&#39;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 09:19:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/topics/gis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Web Mapping with Free Software Tools</title>
      <link>/post/web-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 09:19:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/web-mapping/</guid>
      <description>Introduction GIS in a nutshell Desirable features of a web mapping platform Set up your data for mapping Google Maps QGIS and the qgis2web plugin RStudio and the R Leaflet Package In conclusion   Reading time: 36 minute(s) @ 200 WPM.
   Introduction Web mapping is an application of geographic information systems (GIS) that involves the creation of interactive digital maps displayed and manipulated through a web browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Maps with R</title>
      <link>/post/making-maps-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 13:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/making-maps-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Making maps on a computer has traditionally required the use of desktop geographic information system (GIS) software such as ArcGIS or QGIS. An alternative is to use R, a free software environment for statistical computing and graphics. R has many features that allow it to read GIS data and produce both static and interactive maps. This document (which is an R Notebook) shows how to make maps with R and RStudio, using R base graphics and the maps and mapdata packages, in addition to the leaflet and tmap packages.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
