<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reproducible Research on Richard A. Lent, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>https://richardlent.github.io/tags/reproducible-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reproducible Research on Richard A. Lent, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Richard A. Lent. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 11:56:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://richardlent.github.io/tags/reproducible-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Musings on blogdown and Hugo</title>
      <link>https://richardlent.github.io/post/musings-on-blogdown-and-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 11:56:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardlent.github.io/post/musings-on-blogdown-and-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Reading time: 4 minute(s) @ 200 WPM.
I am a huge fan of R and RStudio, especially relative to their use in creating reproducible research (see RStudio as a Research and Writing Platform). I was thus thrilled to learn that a new R package, blogdown, was being developed for producing websites from R Markdown files using RStudio and the static website generator, Hugo.
This website was built and is maintained using blogdown and Hugo running inside of RStudio, and is hosted on GitHub Pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Markdown Test</title>
      <link>https://richardlent.github.io/post/r-markdown-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 14:20:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardlent.github.io/post/r-markdown-test/</guid>
      <description>Reading time: 2 minute(s) @ 200 WPM.
Yes, it doth work. The blogdown package can nicely deal with R Markdown containing embedded R code for production of statistical analyses and graphics.
But.
It cannot deal with R Notebooks, which contain a special flavor of R Markdown allowing for interactive display of R code alongside the results they produce. R Notebooks, when rendered into HTML, produce a special file named *.nb.html to signify that they are an HTML notebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habitat structure and phenotypic variation in the invading butterfly Coenonympha tullia</title>
      <link>https://richardlent.github.io/post/habitat-structure-and-phenotypic-variation-in-the-invading-butterfly-coenonympha-tullia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 11:18:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardlent.github.io/post/habitat-structure-and-phenotypic-variation-in-the-invading-butterfly-coenonympha-tullia/</guid>
      <description>The R Notebook Habitat structure and phenotypic variation in the invading butterfly Coenonympha tullia is a mockup of a scientific paper (although the field data are real) to illustrate the use of R Notebooks as a means of creating reproducible research. The objective is to produce publication-quality output, in HTML, PDF, and Microsoft Word formats, with text, literature citations, a formatted bibliography, statistical analyses, tables, and graphics, all from one, plain-text R Notebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio as a Research and Writing Platform</title>
      <link>https://richardlent.github.io/post/rstudio-as-a-research-and-writing-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 14:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardlent.github.io/post/rstudio-as-a-research-and-writing-platform/</guid>
      <description>Reproducible Research Software Installation Rendering Documents in RStudio Writing and Citing in RStudio R Notebooks Reproducible Research Revisited Coda I: Python Coda II: Inspirational Quotes About Data     Reading time: 22 minute(s) @ 200 WPM.
R (r-project.org) is a programming language and software platform for statistical computing and graphics, widely used in academia and industry (see An Introduction to R). RStudio is an integrated development environment for R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>