<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graphics on Richard A. Lent, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>/tags/graphics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Graphics on Richard A. Lent, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 and beyond by Richard A. Lent. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 09:19:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/graphics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Mapping with Free Software Tools</title>
      <link>/post/web-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 09:19:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/web-mapping/</guid>
      <description>Introduction GIS in a nutshell Desirable features of a web mapping platform Set up your data for mapping Google Maps QGIS and the qgis2web plugin RStudio and the R Leaflet Package In conclusion   Reading time: 24 minute(s) @ 200 WPM.
   Introduction Web mapping is an application of geographic information systems (GIS) that involves the creation of interactive digital maps displayed and manipulated through a web browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multivariate Analysis with R</title>
      <link>/post/multivariate-analysis-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 09:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/multivariate-analysis-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Preliminaries Multivariate data A map Distance matrices Cluster analysis Mantel test Multidimensional scaling Principal components analysis Discriminant function analysis Epilogue      Reading time: 32 minute(s) @ 200 WPM.
Preliminaries  At some time or another, most users of statistics find themselves sitting in front of a large pile of computer output with the realization that it tells them nothing that they really want to know. — Multivariate Statistical Methods: A Primer, fourth edition (2017)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to R</title>
      <link>/post/introduction-to-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 16:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/introduction-to-r/</guid>
      <description>Prologue Getting a feel for R The console Function calls and arguments HINT: Getting help  Some graphics HINT: Command history and workspace   Getting data into R Data frames Creating data frames HINT: Data management in R and RStudio.   Exploratory data analysis Scatterplot matrix HINT: R packages  Summary statistics and data screening Box plots Stem-and-leaf display Categorical variables: factors Some confirmatory analysis  More graphics R scripts (command files) An R menu system: R-commander Epilogue      Reading time: 23 minute(s) @ 200 WPM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Maps with R</title>
      <link>/post/making-maps-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 13:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/making-maps-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Making maps on a computer has traditionally required the use of desktop geographic information system (GIS) software such as ArcGIS or QGIS. An alternative is to use R, a free software environment for statistical computing and graphics. R has many features that allow it to read GIS data and produce both static and interactive maps. This document (which is an R Notebook) shows how to make maps with R and RStudio, using R base graphics and the maps and mapdata packages, in addition to the leaflet and tmap packages.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>