<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Richard A. Lent, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>/topics/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Richard A. Lent, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Richard A. Lent. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 11:56:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/topics/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Musings on blogdown and Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/musings-on-blogdown-and-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 11:56:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/musings-on-blogdown-and-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Reading time: 4 minute(s) @ 200 WPM.
I am a huge fan of R and RStudio, especially relative to their use in creating reproducible research (see RStudio as a Research and Writing Platform). I was thus thrilled to learn that a new R package, blogdown, was being developed for producing websites from R Markdown files using RStudio and the static website generator, Hugo.
This website was built and is maintained using blogdown and Hugo running inside of RStudio, and is hosted on GitHub Pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plain Text Workflow</title>
      <link>/post/the-plain-text-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 15:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-plain-text-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Reading time: 12 minute(s) @ 200 WPM.
The Plain Text Workflow is an alternative to writing with a word processor. Mind you, I said writing, not typesetting or formatting, which is a major part of what word processors do. The idea of the plain text workflow is that you separate the act of writing from that of producing a formatted, typeset final document. You initially capture your words using a plain text editor, perhaps using a lightweight formatting language like Markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Search</title>
      <link>/post/google-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 14:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/google-search/</guid>
      <description>Reading time: 2 minute(s) @ 200 WPM.
Following the directions for Google’s Custom Search Engine, with additional help from How I added search to my static blog, I have added a local search function to this website. It’s on the sidebar menu, with an adorable magnifying glass icon from Font Awesome Icons, and it basically works.
This search function will, in all likelihood, probably search only the specific content of richardlent.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>