<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Richard A. Lent, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>https://richardlent.github.io/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Richard A. Lent, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Richard A. Lent. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 13:45:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://richardlent.github.io/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Multivariate Analysis with R</title>
      <link>https://richardlent.github.io/post/multivariate-analysis-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 13:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardlent.github.io/post/multivariate-analysis-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Preliminaries Multivariate data A map Distance matrices Cluster analysis Mantel test Multidimensional scaling Principal components analysis Discriminant function analysis Epilogue     Reading time: 32 minute(s) @ 200 WPM.
Preliminaries  At some time or another, most users of statistics find themselves sitting in front of a large pile of computer output with the realization that it tells them nothing that they really want to know. — Multivariate Statistical Methods: A Primer, fourth edition (2017)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to R</title>
      <link>https://richardlent.github.io/post/introduction-to-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 16:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardlent.github.io/post/introduction-to-r/</guid>
      <description>Prologue Getting a feel for R The console Function calls and arguments HINT: Getting help  Some graphics HINT: Command history and workspace   Getting data into R Data frames Creating data frames HINT: Data management in R and RStudio.   Exploratory data analysis Scatterplot matrix HINT: R packages  Summary statistics and data screening Box plots Stem-and-leaf display Categorical variables: factors Some confirmatory analysis  More graphics R scripts (command files) An R menu system: R-commander Epilogue     Reading time: 23 minute(s) @ 200 WPM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An R script for calculating the reading time of an R Markdown file</title>
      <link>https://richardlent.github.io/post/an-r-script-for-calculating-reading-time-of-an-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardlent.github.io/post/an-r-script-for-calculating-reading-time-of-an-article/</guid>
      <description>Reading time: 2 minute(s) @ 200 WPM.
To see how we just did that, read on.
Because psychological research tells us that including estimated reading times can increase reader engagement with digital content, I decided to include reading times for my riveting posts.
So I wrote a simple R script. Here it is, as an R code chunk:
```{r echo=FALSE} bytes  The script is very simple, such that even I could program it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Markdown Test</title>
      <link>https://richardlent.github.io/post/r-markdown-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 14:20:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardlent.github.io/post/r-markdown-test/</guid>
      <description>Reading time: 2 minute(s) @ 200 WPM.
Yes, it doth work. The blogdown package can nicely deal with R Markdown containing embedded R code for production of statistical analyses and graphics.
But.
It cannot deal with R Notebooks, which contain a special flavor of R Markdown allowing for interactive display of R code alongside the results they produce. R Notebooks, when rendered into HTML, produce a special file named *.nb.html to signify that they are an HTML notebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Notebook Example with R, Python, and BibTeX</title>
      <link>https://richardlent.github.io/post/r-notebook-example-with-r-python-and-bibtex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 12:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardlent.github.io/post/r-notebook-example-with-r-python-and-bibtex/</guid>
      <description>The accompanying R Notebook is a simple example that combines R code chunks, Python code chunks, and BibTeX literature citations in one R Markdown document.
For additional information please see RStudio as a Research and Writing Platform.
Click here to read the notebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio as a Research and Writing Platform</title>
      <link>https://richardlent.github.io/post/rstudio-as-a-research-and-writing-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 14:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richardlent.github.io/post/rstudio-as-a-research-and-writing-platform/</guid>
      <description>Reproducible Research Software Installation Rendering Documents in RStudio Writing and Citing in RStudio R Notebooks Reproducible Research Revisited Coda I: Python Coda II: Inspirational Quotes About Data     Reading time: 22 minute(s) @ 200 WPM.
R (r-project.org) is a programming language and software platform for statistical computing and graphics, widely used in academia and industry (see An Introduction to R). RStudio is an integrated development environment for R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>